[Music]
hi my name is Brian nilson I'm a program
manager within the business Central team
and I'm going to tell you about what's
new in financial
management it's going to be a short
video where I will tell you about the
new
features uh they are already covered in
other videos that we will link to in the
captions uh it's just to let you know
that we actually did improve features in
financial management
the first feature that we have added is
subscription billing which is a module
that allows you to do recurring
invoicing for contracts for services
that you provide to your
customer it can also be uh creating
invoices for expenses that you incur
recurringly from your
vendors it has modules to allow you to
to set the frequency the periods that
are built the renewal um and or expiry
period it has a deferral module so you
can control when you recognize revenue
or expenses from these contracts that
you have invoiced and it has a module uh
recurring uh billing where you can
control what it is that you're invoicing
in a given period so it has a lot of
features that will allow you to be
flexible in how you want to do uh
recurring billing it comes with a set of
standard reports and in
25.2 we will provide you with Excel
reports uh a new word layout and a
powerbi app which means that you will
have embedded powerbi reporting for
subscription billing but that will be in
the next minor and sometime soon maybe
the next release we will also do
automated building so you can set it up
once and let it
run we have a very small new feature
that will help you if you're running a
lot of scenarios where you're adding GL
lines to your sales or purchase
documents you set it up in the sales and
receivables or purchase and payables
setup it's a small toggle that says uh
default uh quantity for G lines it will
be set to one if you toggle it on and
you don't have to type it in
manually just like we did for the item
default
quantity we are going to deliver powerbi
apps for six areas including Finance
sales and purchase and so on the finance
powerbi app includes 14 reports and they
will be found as embedded reports in the
product so you can call up financial
information they will contain overview
they will contain kpis and they will
contain The Ledger entry so you can
drill down into the granular records for
these reports but it's all covered in a
separate
session we also have for fixed assets um
this is the first module where we have
done it we have created a query it's a
query based on a star schema so that you
can query the fixed asset uh Ledger
entries and do your own views on on top
of that either to complement the reports
that are there or for a quick fact
finding um and the benefit is that it it
is multiple tables that are are qued at
the same time so it's not just the table
you see on the page and it's good for
for fact finding or validating your
data the third thing we did for uh
reporting in the financial area is that
we added more templates for the
financial reporting module where you
combine row definitions with column
definitions so you can create your own
reports or variant of reports you can
also take the templates and start
creating your
own um there are five predefined reports
balance and income statement detailed or
summarized and there's a trial balance
with just the posting entries just to
get you started but of course uh you can
combine this as you want there's new
docs content for all of this so that you
can see what are the reports about and
also how do you create your own for for
your business and the setup that you
have and some tips and tricks on how to
uh create the best reports in the
financial reporting
module so there are features in the
financial management area there's
subscription billing there's powerbi
reports and there's analytics in uh in
various new uh features so watch the
videos that are linked in the caption
below thank you for watching